<tool id="samconverter4" name="SAMConverter4" version="4.0">
  <description>Converts a SAM format alignment into a binary tagsOnPhysicalMap (.topm) </description>

  <command>
		source $__tool_directory__/module_tassel4.sh;
		$__tool_directory__/SAMConverter4.sh $input $output $logfile
  </command>

  <inputs>
    <param name="input" type="data" format="sam" label="SAM format alignment" />
  </inputs>

  <outputs>
    <data format="txt" name="output" label="Tassel4 Output TagsOnPhysicalMap (.topm) (Input for FastqToTBT and Discovery SNP Plugin)"/> 
    <data format="txt" name="logfile" label="Tassel4 SAMConverter logfile"/> 
  </outputs>
  <help>
  
  .. class:: infomark

**Program encapsulated in Galaxy by South Green**

.. class:: infomark

**Tassel**

-----

==========
 Overview
==========

**TASSEL-GBS: A High Capacity Genotyping by Sequencing Analysis Pipeline**

**SAMConverter Plugin (Tassel 4.0)**

Converts a SAM format alignment (.sam) file produced by one of the aligners, BWA or bowtie2, into a binary tagsOnPhysicalMap (.topm) file that can be used by the TagsToSNPByAlignmentPlugin for calling SNPs. 

**The commonly used parameters with default value setting**::

    -i    Alignment file in SAM format (.sam) produced by BWA or bowtie2.
    -o    Output TagsOnPhysicalMap (TOPM) file that can be used by the TagsToSNPByAlignmentPlugin for calling SNPs (or by the SeqToTBTHDF5Plugin or FastqToTBTPlugin as a master tag list). 

In order for this step to work correctly, the chromosome names (sequence headers) in the FASTA reference
genome file used as input to BWA or bowtie2 must be integers, e.g., >1, >2, or >3. We currently do not have
any provision for text names such as >chrom1, >chrom2, >chrom3, etc. The only exception is that we do allow
usage of the prefix “chr” so that >chr1, >chr2, >chr3, etc. are acceptable headers. In the case of non-numerical
chromosome names (X, Y, mt, cp) or polyploid genomes, you will need to rename them as integers (and keep
track of how your new names back-translate).

-----

For further informations, please visite the website of TASSEL_.

.. _TASSEL: http://www.maizegenetics.net/#!tassel/c17q9

  	</help>
	<citations>
    	<citation type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0090346</citation> 
  	</citations>
</tool>